<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>customjs on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/customjs.html</link><description>Recent content in customjs on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/customjs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Find lost things in Obsidian with the CustomJS plugin</title><link>/2023/09/14/find-lost-things-in-obsidian-with-customjs.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/09/14/find-lost-things-in-obsidian-with-customjs.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://obsidian.md">Obsidian&lt;/a> is a lovely note-taking tool that I use for all the things.
It is flexible and plastic in a really lovely way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But over time (or due to overuse of bulk updates in VSCode), you can end up with images that aren&amp;rsquo;t referenced anywhere, or links to images that don&amp;rsquo;t exist (or are not where the note expects them to be).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first attempt at making a list of lost things used &lt;a href="https://github.com/blacksmithgu/obsidian-dataview">dataview&lt;/a>, but I had a few problems with it: it was generally slow to render (not surprising, it was doing a lot), and due to that slowness, the note would flicker when I opened it on my tablet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this attempt, I&amp;rsquo;m using an &lt;a href="https://github.com/saml-dev/obsidian-custom-js#invocable-scripts">invokable scripts&lt;/a> from the &lt;a href="https://github.com/saml-dev/obsidian-custom-js">CustomJS&lt;/a> plugin to update/replace the conent of a note.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The general idea: I run the script (command), it updates/replaces the contents of a note. I can review that note and decide if unreferenced files should be deleted, or if links need to be fixed, etc. I can run the script again to verify that I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed the problem, or I can forget about it until the next time I feel like I should tidy things up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/ebullient/9574764676b96530659e4f65945d3392">gist&lt;/a> is shown below the fold (see more).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>