<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>obsidian on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/obsidian.html</link><description>Recent content in obsidian on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/obsidian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Obsidian.md plugin: Task Collector</title><link>/2021/10/10/obsidian-md-plugin-task-collector.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/10/obsidian-md-plugin-task-collector.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I've had a lovely time working with &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md">Obsidian.md&lt;/a>. Some day I will have to do a proper write-up of how I'm using it to organize my brain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The TL;DR version is that I had a mental log-jam in March, when the kids finished their first D&amp;amp;D campaign while I was also in the middle of starting some new things for the day job. I made a vault for D&amp;amp;D, and dumped &lt;em>ALL&lt;/em> of the stuff there (removing it from the scattering of notes I had in places, and netting out all the relationships I kind of had just lying around in my head). I made another vault for the rest of what is in my brain, and that is proceeding at a slower pace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any event, the way things have evolved, I needed a plugin that did something a little differently for a specific kind of task that is associated with a project, so I created the &lt;a href="https://github.com/ebullient/obsidian-task-collector">Task Collector&lt;/a> plugin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some notes about jitpack</title><link>/2021/08/04/some-notes-about-jitpack.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/08/04/some-notes-about-jitpack.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I created another weird side project, this one only sort of related to monsters. I do (still) use FightClub5 as a player, and to manage what my players have to deal with / look at for our campaigns. &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md">Obsidian&lt;/a> has started to take over as campaign manager, because encounters are created/set up/and tracked in Roll20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been working with &lt;a href="https://github.com/kinkofer/FightClub5eXML/">https://github.com/kinkofer/FightClub5eXML/&lt;/a> to stitch together the sources I want for FightClub5 (the source for these XML files in turn is &lt;a href="https://5e.tools/,">https://5e.tools/,&lt;/a> which is pretty good, too).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing lead to another, and time passed, and I worked on the Quarkus CLI, and then I had the idea to write my own client that could do all of the steps required (validate the xml, merge/combine/filter with XSLT) and additionally convert the output into markdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy Happy!&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="github-card" data-github="ebullient/fc5-convert-cli" data-width="400" data-height="" data-theme="default">&lt;/div>
&lt;script src="//cdn.jsdelivr.net/github-cards/latest/widget.js">&lt;/script></description></item></channel></rss>