<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/linux.html</link><description>Recent content in linux on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Movies schmovies</title><link>/2010/04/01/movies-schmovies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/01/movies-schmovies.html</guid><description>Want to get DVDs playing on the laptop that is running gentoo that I'll only have to use for a few more days before I get a new shiny (purple!) one. I know, makes no sense.. but hey, learning is good, right? Use xine-ui. It got the farthest first. Make sure your region is set Go through the few hoops you need to get raw i/o working. I pegged/tanked RAM w/o raw access -- every player segfaulted as a result (mplayer, xine, vlc). Use the raw device. If it's an encrypted DVD (and you have libdvdcss installed), I found that I needed to change something in my environment to get it to correctly decrypt the disk: export DVDCSS_METHOD=disc -- I did it on the command line since I was just testing. Setting this finally let the DVD play.. with dropped frames all over the place.. but still.. progress! And last, but not least, the simplest instruction from xine's help: change the niceness level of xine.. nice --5 xine And poof! movie! with menu! rock on</description></item><item><title>Amen for schedtool</title><link>/2010/01/13/amen-for-schedtool.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/01/13/amen-for-schedtool.html</guid><description> How did I not know about this sooner? Trying to build a particularly large maven project would consume so much CPU that my poor laptop would quit because it was sweating too much. I used schedtool to set an affinity to only one of the two CPUs available on my dual-core laptop for the shell I used to launch the build, and voila! Things don't get as hot, and my system stays responsive. *phew!* schedtool</description></item><item><title>Handy CD reading/writing/ripping stuff</title><link>/2004/12/01/handy-cd-readingwritingripping-stuff.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/12/01/handy-cd-readingwritingripping-stuff.html</guid><description> ISO, CDR, and CDRW in Linux [cpqlinux.com]
An old page, but full of handy tips (more like quick references) nonetheless.
Just in case, it's also here. [waybackmachine.org]
Also:
HOWTO ATAPI CD Burning [gentoo-wiki.com] CD burning with a 2.6 kernel [www.debian-administration.org]</description></item><item><title>Helpful stuff for kernel 2.6.x and X (mice/keyboard)</title><link>/2004/02/19/helpful-stuff-for-kernel-26x-and-x-micekeyboard.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/02/19/helpful-stuff-for-kernel-26x-and-x-micekeyboard.html</guid><description> Linux: 2.6 Input Drivers FAQ
Didn't want to lose it.. Additional keyboard stuff:
Keyboard-and-Console-HOWTO</description></item></channel></rss>