<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>craft on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/craft.html</link><description>Recent content in craft on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/craft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DIY dice cauldron</title><link>/2021/02/14/dice-cauldron.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/02/14/dice-cauldron.html</guid><description>Not alot of description around this one. Let's just say it's .. crochet engineering? I don't know. I was practicing crocheting circles as the base for baskets, and the pattern I was following, if you held it up to the light, had this nice convenient kind of spiral place where you could totally add a chain&amp;hellip;
And things kind of grew from there.
The cauldron in progress Closed Open</description></item><item><title>DIY paper planner - with a cover</title><link>/2013/09/24/diy-paper-planner-with-a-cover.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/09/24/diy-paper-planner-with-a-cover.html</guid><description>&lt;p>So. It took one day, and I had to make a cover. I couldn't help myself. Thankfully, I have more scrapbooking supplies lying around than I know what to do with, so it didn't take too long. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted pockets. I wanted pseudo-lamination. I wanted something that could still flex backwards. No problem, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DIY paper planner</title><link>/2013/09/23/diy-paper-planner.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/09/23/diy-paper-planner.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="/images/4t.png" class="right-box" title="Cover view" alt="Cover view" />
&lt;p>Those that have known me for a long time know that I am a sucker for planner. The trouble is that I don't use them much beyond the new planner honeymoon period (for any number of reasons). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>With two kids and a change of house coming, I needed to do something for my overloaded brain, and no combination of apps on the phone is doing the job. Hubby and I do use Google calendars for a somewhat shared brain (at least with regard to who should be where and when), but I don't like Google tasks much (and can't unload work brain there, anyway). I also prefer hand-written lists and notes: I end up with little notes everywhere which doesn't help when you're already feeling overwhelmed!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I stumbled on &lt;span class="caps">DIY&lt;/span> planner printables on Pinterest, and it got me thinking. None of the ones I saw were quite right, and I realized a few reasons why:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>they tend to be over-regimented&lt;/li>
&lt;li>many split up or squish the weekend in the week view&lt;/li>
&lt;li>many use a lot of color, which is nice, but I have a black and white laser printer, so all that flash is lost on me&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>With all of that in mind, I made my own. It is sparse and unadorned, and has few boxes dedicated to this or that kind of note (to do, shopping list, contact list, etc.). This thing is basically all a to-do list of sorts, and I wanted to give myself room (with pen/pencil) to evolve how it works.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>