<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>conference on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/conference.html</link><description>Recent content in conference on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mechanics of Metrics, at DevNexus</title><link>/2021/03/05/DevNexus-2021-mechanics-of-metrics.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/03/05/DevNexus-2021-mechanics-of-metrics.html</guid><description>A reframing of the metrics talk, with a much more detailed look at how emitted metrics are aggregated by PromQL / Grafana dashboards.
I quite like this one, to be honest.</description></item><item><title>Metrics for the win! at J4K Conference</title><link>/2020/11/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-j4k.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/11/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-j4k.html</guid><description>A longer form of Metrics for the Win! recorded for J4K, which occurred in October of 2020.</description></item><item><title>D&amp;D and Metrics: an unexpected journey</title><link>/2020/11/09/an-unexpected-journey-with-metrics.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/11/09/an-unexpected-journey-with-metrics.html</guid><description>I was asked, based solely on the abstract for my 2020 DevNexus talk, if I would be interested in writing an article on the topic. I agreed. The resulting article was published in Germina, in the September 2020 issue of Java Magazin, with &amp;ldquo;Dungeons and Dragons&amp;rdquo; as the title. I have a lovely hard-copy in my office.
The English version has also now been published at JaxEnter, &amp;ldquo;Monsters in combat: exploring application metrics with D&amp;amp;D&amp;rdquo;.
I hope you enjoy it.</description></item><item><title>Metrics for the win! at JConf</title><link>/2020/10/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-jconf.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-jconf.html</guid><description>A fully online recorded talk, sliding in at just 30 minutes, for JConf in the fall of 2020.</description></item><item><title>Monsters and Metrics at SpringOne 2019</title><link>/2019/10/23/springone-monsters-metrics.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/10/23/springone-monsters-metrics.html</guid><description>Two things collided in my brain this year ahead of SpringOne: Preparing a new talk from scratch covering the Micrometer (and the related Spring implementation), and learning everything I needed to know to be a Dungeon Master for my 10-year-old son and his friends.
Thanks to a brilliant suggestion from a friend, these two things collided in the talk, too. Which lightened the mental load (or at least reduced the amount of full stack swapping going on).
Github repository: ebullient/monster-combat with Spring Boot 2, WebFlux, and Micrometer</description></item><item><title>Cloud-Native Security for Java: Code @ Think</title><link>/2019/02/16/Code-Think-CloudNative-Security.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/02/16/Code-Think-CloudNative-Security.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Billy and I put together a tidy little talk about Cloud-Native
Security for Java applications to give at &amp;ldquo;Code @ Think&amp;rdquo; during
the annual IBM Think Conference.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Java Ecosystem Collision: What is the Future of Cloud Native?</title><link>/2018/04/19/CFSummit-CloudNative.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/04/19/CFSummit-CloudNative.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Attempt number two for the evolution of Cloud Native, given at CF Summit 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cfna18.sched.com/event/DdaB/the-java-ecosystem-collision-what-is-the-future-of-cloud-native-erin-schnabel-ibm">The Java Ecosystem Collision: What is the Future of Cloud Native? - Erin Schnabel, IBM&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NkBNLkmldnI" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>What is a Cloud Native application, anyway?</title><link>/2018/03/10/IndexConf-CloudNative.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/03/10/IndexConf-CloudNative.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I gave a few talks at &lt;strong>Index&lt;/strong> Developer Conference in San Francisco:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Workshop! Game-On Text Adventure re-presented in lab form, with some lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Testing Cloud Native Applications&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What is a Cloud Native Application, anyway? My first attempt at talking about what is going on with Cloud Native applications these days.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Doing the scary thing: Mainstage at SpringOne</title><link>/2017/12/08/SpringOne.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/12/08/SpringOne.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I will absolutely confess that it was daunting to start with, but that once I was out on the stage, everything was fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will also confess to ad nauseum rehearsal. To reciting what I had to cram into two segments (one only 2 minutes long, and the other 2 minutes and 30 seconds) to every inanimate object in my hotel room: lamps, laptops, mirrors, showerheads, and I'm pretty sure my pillow while I was sleeping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn't really wrap my head around what I wanted to say until the night before. Things just didn't fall into place before then. But hey, I lived! It was quite the experience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>