<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jekyll on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/jekyll.html</link><description>Recent content in jekyll on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Jekyll and GitBook to Hugo and Asciidoc, care of Github Actions</title><link>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This won't be a super chatty post. We have two websites for Game On! (our microservices text adventure): a jekyll-based markdown blog and a legacy-gitbook-based asciidoc book. For various reason, I want to combine them,and I woukd rather not spend gobs of time converting between markdown and asciidoc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep things quick: I knew I wanted a static site generator, and I've used hugo before and found it fast, straight-forward and unconfusing. So in my mind, I'd already picked hugo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jekyll templates with Docker containers</title><link>/2017/05/02/jekyll.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/02/jekyll.html</guid><description>&lt;p>It took me a few tries (divided attention, grr), but I realized that after messing with blogs for over 10 years, I've seen all the things! Way back in the beginning was Movable Type (which I didn't realize was still a thing), followed by PHP-based CMS like Textpattern and Nucleus CMS, and then a brief flirtation with Blogger (someone made me do it). I have somehow avoided ever having to maintain templates for WordPress (?!). These systems all come back to some pretty basic concepts around templating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one snag was loathing having to do anything with ruby. I have never had anything but grief and pain installing ruby anywhere. But hey! We have docker now! Put it in a container and forget about it. WOOT!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>