<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/blog.html</link><description>Recent content in blog on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hugo with markdown and asciidoc</title><link>/2020/03/06/hugo-with-markdown-and-asciidoc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/03/06/hugo-with-markdown-and-asciidoc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>All done!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building on &lt;a href="/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html">the previous post&lt;/a>, here is a summary of what I had to do to collapse two sites (one a date-oriented blog, and the other an outline-based gitbook) into a single site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Jekyll and GitBook to Hugo and Asciidoc, care of Github Actions</title><link>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This won&amp;rsquo;t be a super chatty post. We have two websites for Game On! (our microservices text adventure): a jekyll-based markdown blog and a legacy-gitbook-based asciidoc book. For various reason, I want to combine them,and I woukd rather not spend gobs of time converting between markdown and asciidoc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep things quick: I knew I wanted a static site generator, and I&amp;rsquo;ve used hugo before and found it fast, straight-forward and unconfusing. So in my mind, I&amp;rsquo;d already picked hugo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jekyll templates with Docker containers</title><link>/2017/05/02/jekyll.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/02/jekyll.html</guid><description>&lt;p>It took me a few tries (divided attention, grr), but I realized that after messing with blogs for over 10 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen all the things! Way back in the beginning was Movable Type (which I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize was still a thing), followed by PHP-based CMS like Textpattern and Nucleus CMS, and then a brief flirtation with Blogger (someone made me do it). I have somehow avoided ever having to maintain templates for WordPress (?!). These systems all come back to some pretty basic concepts around templating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one snag was loathing having to do anything with ruby. I have never had anything but grief and pain installing ruby anywhere. But hey! We have docker now! Put it in a container and forget about it. WOOT!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From then to now.. blogs over 12 years</title><link>/2017/05/01/blogs.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/01/blogs.html</guid><description>Yes, I confess, I did .. umm.. censor my blogs over the years. When facebook arrived, blog posts about nasty headaches and reactions to the latest headlines could all go away. The exodus of content continued with the advent of Twitter. Which left this blog, which I&amp;rsquo;ve tended on and off for close to 14 years, in the lurch!
There is also the small matter of how much time I have to spend on blog posts between work, kids, and this mammoth garden we have going in the back yard. The mammoth garden is totally my fault, we started it as an excuse to get me outside. It worked.
However, it has become obvious that a return to blogging is overdue. To start with, Game On! needed a blog! We kept having little tidbits to share, that needed a home. I made an initial foray into creating a blog with Jekyll to build a new blog for Game On!. I kind of liked how that worked, AND it meant I could stop having to edit posts via the web, and so I&amp;rsquo;ve now brought that to my own blog, too.
Next post: the jekyll stuff.</description></item><item><title>TXP Hack: centralizing priv lookups</title><link>/2005/06/24/TXP-check-privs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/06/24/TXP-check-privs.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I use &lt;span class="caps">HTTP&lt;/span> Auth for one of my Textpattern installations, and so, I wanted people that could get to the textpattern pages to have, by default, staff writer permissions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TXP Hack: Using TXP Excerpts like MT</title><link>/2005/03/06/MT-excerpts-in-TXP.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/03/06/MT-excerpts-in-TXP.html</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things I used heavily in MT was the body/extended body trick. I wanted to continue that with Textpattern, but it involved some hacks to how &lt;span class="caps">TXP &lt;/span>handles excerpts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TXP Hack: MT-Macro like function in textpattern</title><link>/2005/02/23/MT-macro-in-TXP.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/02/23/MT-macro-in-TXP.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple hack to add one of my favorite MT-plugins, Brad Choate's &lt;a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/weblog/2002/08/12/mtmacro">&lt;span class="caps">MTM&lt;/span>acros&lt;/a> &lt;span class="attribute">[&lt;a href="http://www.bradchoate.com">bradchoate.com&lt;/a>]&lt;/span>, to textpattern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Granted, I didn't pull the entire kaboodle. This doesn't do fun container logic and acronym matching, etc. But it does do simple string replacement, which is what I used it for (e.g. smilies and pretty attributions).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>