<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/blog.html</link><description>Recent content in blog on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hugo with markdown and asciidoc</title><link>/2020/03/06/hugo-with-markdown-and-asciidoc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/03/06/hugo-with-markdown-and-asciidoc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>All done!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building on &lt;a href="/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html">the previous post&lt;/a>, here is a summary of what I had to do to collapse two sites (one a date-oriented blog, and the other an outline-based gitbook) into a single site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Jekyll and GitBook to Hugo and Asciidoc, care of Github Actions</title><link>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This won't be a super chatty post. We have two websites for Game On! (our microservices text adventure): a jekyll-based markdown blog and a legacy-gitbook-based asciidoc book. For various reason, I want to combine them,and I woukd rather not spend gobs of time converting between markdown and asciidoc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep things quick: I knew I wanted a static site generator, and I've used hugo before and found it fast, straight-forward and unconfusing. So in my mind, I'd already picked hugo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From then to now.. blogs over 12 years</title><link>/2017/05/01/blogs.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/01/blogs.html</guid><description>Yes, I confess, I did .. umm.. censor my blogs over the years. When facebook arrived, blog posts about nasty headaches and reactions to the latest headlines could all go away. The exodus of content continued with the advent of Twitter. Which left this blog, which I've tended on and off for close to 14 years, in the lurch!
There is also the small matter of how much time I have to spend on blog posts between work, kids, and this mammoth garden we have going in the back yard. The mammoth garden is totally my fault, we started it as an excuse to get me outside. It worked.
However, it has become obvious that a return to blogging is overdue. To start with, Game On! needed a blog! We kept having little tidbits to share, that needed a home. I made an initial foray into creating a blog with Jekyll to build a new blog for Game On!. I kind of liked how that worked, AND it meant I could stop having to edit posts via the web, and so I've now brought that to my own blog, too.
Next post: the jekyll stuff.</description></item></channel></rss>