<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ebullient·works</title><link>/posts.html</link><description>Recent content in Posts on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metrics for the win! at J4K Conference</title><link>/2020/11/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-j4k.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/11/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-j4k.html</guid><description>A longer form of Metrics for the Win! recorded for J4K, which occurred in October of 2020.</description></item><item><title>D&amp;D and Metrics: an unexpected journey</title><link>/2020/11/09/an-unexpected-journey-with-metrics.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/11/09/an-unexpected-journey-with-metrics.html</guid><description>I was asked, based solely on the abstract for my 2020 DevNexus talk, if I would be interested in writing an article on the topic. I agreed. The resulting article was published in Germina, in the September 2020 issue of Java Magazin, with &amp;ldquo;Dungeons and Dragons&amp;rdquo; as the title. I have a lovely hard-copy in my office.
The English version has also now been published at JaxEnter, &amp;ldquo;Monsters in combat: exploring application metrics with D&amp;amp;D&amp;rdquo;.
I hope you enjoy it.</description></item><item><title>Metrics for the win! at JConf</title><link>/2020/10/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-jconf.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/10/12/metrics-for-the-win-at-jconf.html</guid><description>A fully online recorded talk, sliding in at just 30 minutes, for JConf in the fall of 2020.</description></item><item><title>Hugo with markdown and asciidoc</title><link>/2020/03/06/hugo-with-markdown-and-asciidoc.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/03/06/hugo-with-markdown-and-asciidoc.html</guid><description>&lt;p>All done!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building on &lt;a href="/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html">the previous post&lt;/a>, here is a summary of what I had to do to collapse two sites (one a date-oriented blog, and the other an outline-based gitbook) into a single site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Jekyll and GitBook to Hugo and Asciidoc, care of Github Actions</title><link>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/08/from-jekyll-and-gitbook-to-hugo-and-asciidoc-care-of-github-actions.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This won't be a super chatty post. We have two websites for Game On! (our microservices text adventure): a jekyll-based markdown blog and a legacy-gitbook-based asciidoc book. For various reason, I want to combine them,and I woukd rather not spend gobs of time converting between markdown and asciidoc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To keep things quick: I knew I wanted a static site generator, and I've used hugo before and found it fast, straight-forward and unconfusing. So in my mind, I'd already picked hugo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scripts for the win! Updating git repositories for the lazy.</title><link>/2019/10/25/scripts-for-the-win-updating-git-repositories-for-the-lazy.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/10/25/scripts-for-the-win-updating-git-repositories-for-the-lazy.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I love scripts! I treat them as my extended memory. Blog posts used to do this,
but life and children have eaten up the capacity I used to have for writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I thought I would share my latest script for the lazy (which I have now duplicated several times. I know, I know. WET, DRY. I can't be bothered). This script iterates over all of the git repositories in a sub-directory (where I have several related ones), fetches everything, fast-forwards if it can, and otherwise tries to rebase on the upstream branch if there is one that matches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is an extra case statement at the bottom as I inevitably extend this to do
more things specific to this group of projects. This kind of approach grew out
of the scripts written for Game On!, which still work well, and do their extra
duty reminding me what on earth I was doing the last time I worked on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monsters and Metrics at SpringOne 2019</title><link>/2019/10/23/springone-monsters-metrics.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/10/23/springone-monsters-metrics.html</guid><description>Two things collided in my brain this year ahead of SpringOne: Preparing a new talk from scratch covering the Micrometer (and the related Spring implementation), and learning everything I needed to know to be a Dungeon Master for my 10-year-old son and his friends.
Thanks to a brilliant suggestion from a friend, these two things collided in the talk, too. Which lightened the mental load (or at least reduced the amount of full stack swapping going on).
Github repository: ebullient/monster-combat with Spring Boot 2, WebFlux, and Micrometer</description></item><item><title>Debug gulp</title><link>/2018/09/20/debug-gulp.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/09/20/debug-gulp.html</guid><description>&lt;p>A gulp build unhelpfully finished with:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>(node:12030) UnhandledPromiseRejectionWarning: null
(node:12030) UnhandledPromiseRejectionWarning: Unhandled promise rejection. This error originated either by throwing inside of an async function without a catch block, or by rejecting a promise which was not handled with .catch(). (rejection id: 1)
(node:12030) [DEP0018] DeprecationWarning: Unhandled promise rejections are deprecated. In the future, promise rejections that are not handled will terminate the Node.js process with a non-zero exit code.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>I needed to change both my gulpfile and my IDE to be able to follow what
was happening.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a Cloud Native application, anyway?</title><link>/2018/03/10/IndexConf-CloudNative.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/03/10/IndexConf-CloudNative.html</guid><description>This is my first attempt at talking about what is going on with Cloud Native applications these days. Given at IndexConf in San Francisco.</description></item><item><title>Doing the scary thing: Mainstage at SpringOne</title><link>/2017/12/08/SpringOne.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/12/08/SpringOne.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I will absolutely confess that it was daunting to start with, but that once I was out on the stage, everything was fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will also confess to ad nauseum rehearsal. To reciting what I had to cram into two segments (one only 2 minutes long, and the other 2 minutes and 30 seconds) to every inanimate object in my hotel room: lamps, laptops, mirrors, showerheads, and I'm pretty sure my pillow while I was sleeping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn't really wrap my head around what I wanted to say until the night before. Things just didn't fall into place before then. But hey, I lived! It was quite the experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Java EE ebullience — airhacks.fm podcast with Adam Bien</title><link>/2017/11/27/airhacks-fm.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/11/27/airhacks-fm.html</guid><description>I spent an excellent few hours recording a podcast with Adam Bien!</description></item><item><title>Git with edit on an iPad?</title><link>/2017/11/12/git-on-ipad.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/11/12/git-on-ipad.html</guid><description>We shall see how this goes over time, but so far? Oh hell yes.
I am experimenting with a cute little app (I have, sad to say, fallen head over feet into the Apple ecosystem. Other devices might seem cool, but not worth the gymnastics. Ecosystem stickiness is a thing.) that allows me to edit. code. from. my. iPad.
Why would I want to do that?
Device junky that I am, I totes splurged and got an iPad Pro, with its little keyboard. I would really really really like to make more entries to this blog, for example. This is a nice alternative to hauling laptop around. I want to see how far I can push this über tiny device thing, that ALSO happens to have a stylus (yes, I am one of those people that thinks better long-hand). So exciting!
The one challenge with this, in particular, is that I can’t get the Jekyll preview that I could if I were running locally. The iPad Pro is quite the workhorse&amp;hellip; but it doesn’t (yet, ha!) run Docker containers.
Oh, right. The app: Working Copy. It also integrates with iOctocat.</description></item><item><title>Jekyll templates with Docker containers</title><link>/2017/05/02/jekyll.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/02/jekyll.html</guid><description>&lt;p>It took me a few tries (divided attention, grr), but I realized that after messing with blogs for over 10 years, I've seen all the things! Way back in the beginning was Movable Type (which I didn't realize was still a thing), followed by PHP-based CMS like Textpattern and Nucleus CMS, and then a brief flirtation with Blogger (someone made me do it). I have somehow avoided ever having to maintain templates for WordPress (?!). These systems all come back to some pretty basic concepts around templating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one snag was loathing having to do anything with ruby. I have never had anything but grief and pain installing ruby anywhere. But hey! We have docker now! Put it in a container and forget about it. WOOT!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From then to now.. blogs over 12 years</title><link>/2017/05/01/blogs.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/01/blogs.html</guid><description>Yes, I confess, I did .. umm.. censor my blogs over the years. When facebook arrived, blog posts about nasty headaches and reactions to the latest headlines could all go away. The exodus of content continued with the advent of Twitter. Which left this blog, which I've tended on and off for close to 14 years, in the lurch!
There is also the small matter of how much time I have to spend on blog posts between work, kids, and this mammoth garden we have going in the back yard. The mammoth garden is totally my fault, we started it as an excuse to get me outside. It worked.
However, it has become obvious that a return to blogging is overdue. To start with, Game On! needed a blog! We kept having little tidbits to share, that needed a home. I made an initial foray into creating a blog with Jekyll to build a new blog for Game On!. I kind of liked how that worked, AND it meant I could stop having to edit posts via the web, and so I've now brought that to my own blog, too.
Next post: the jekyll stuff.</description></item><item><title>Game On! Explore microservices with a text-based adventure</title><link>/2016/05/16/game-on-explore-microservices-with-a-text-based-adventure.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/05/16/game-on-explore-microservices-with-a-text-based-adventure.html</guid><description>Microservices: the buzz is everywhere. Given the breadth of technologies related to the term, it can be difficult to get a full picture of what a Microservices architecture should look like, or to understand why it is said that microservices architectures both remove and introduce complexity at the same time. Game On! is a throwback text-based adventure built to help you explore microservices concepts.
Continue with post on IBM developerWorks</description></item><item><title>Swagger-first API design</title><link>/2016/01/27/swagger-first-api-design.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/01/27/swagger-first-api-design.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I've been working for the past few months on building Game On! a microservices-based application that is intended to show both what a microservices architecture looks like, and to make it easy for people to play with such a system without having to start from the ground up themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We started with a best-guess set of services, and over time, it became pretty apparent that our first pass at a map building service (the Concierge) was both misleading in purpose and insufficient in function. It did serve its purpose, filling in for service discovery in a way, but we were growing beyond what the service could do. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shell prompt crazy for Git Submodules</title><link>/2015/12/16/shell-prompt-crazy-for-git-submodules.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/12/16/shell-prompt-crazy-for-git-submodules.html</guid><description>I've run a somewhat odd little script to generate my command prompt for years now, sets some colors, adds some indicators of what kind of shell I'm in (sudo or tmux/screen or ssh or.. ).
Given I now have to work with git and submodules, I've revised that to include information provided about git generated by this script: https://github.com/git/git/blob/master/contrib/completion/git-prompt.sh
The difference is worth it, in understanding at a glance what is going on without typing git status or variant every two seconds. ;)
I've also been using some very useful aliases to make working with submodules sane, as documented here: Game On! Advanced Adventures / Git Submodules</description></item><item><title>Microservices and WAS Liberty</title><link>/2015/12/11/microservices-and-was-liberty.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/12/11/microservices-and-was-liberty.html</guid><description>Home to Microservices and WAS Liberty resources, which provide background information, getting started guidance, best practices, and methodologies.
Continue with post on IBM developerWorks</description></item><item><title>Trying to tell the human story...</title><link>/2015/12/08/trying-to-tell-the-human-story.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/12/08/trying-to-tell-the-human-story.html</guid><description>Writing is always hard. Writing technical stuff is hard. Writing technical stuff that doesn't sound like it is a regurgitated text book&amp;#8230; sigh
I've been leading a team working on or with Microservices at IBM (lots of people everywhere are doing things with microservices, this should come as no surprise). We've been specifically looking at how to modernize an existing Java EE application. There are articles about this, but they are all formal, and (to me) preachy.
We're doing the experiment live, so to speak. Taking the crufty Plants By WebSphere application and pulling it apart bit by bit. Our aim is to make sure you have a functional application at all times, and to frankly just share our thoughts as we try it. Let us know what you think.
Blog posts (there will be more): Rules of Engagement Getting started
Articles (longer lived, some procedure): Decomposition Choosing a candidate Breaking the candidate out into its own microservice</description></item><item><title>Which gradle...</title><link>/2015/12/05/which-gradle.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/12/05/which-gradle.html</guid><description> I am lazy. My fingers have habits that are sometimes hard to change.
I've learned to type gradle, like all the time. Now I need to use gradlew, and for some reason this is difficult.
So I wrote a script, that I've now aliased (whichGradle is now obviously on my path):
alias gradle='whichGradle'
which just does this: if [ -x $PWD/gradlew ]; then echo Using $PWD/gradlew $PWD/gradlew $@ else echo Using `which gradle` gradle $@ fi</description></item><item><title>Secure Microservices: API Keys, Access Tokens, and Signed JWTs</title><link>/2015/12/04/secure-microservices-api-keys-access-tokens-and-signed-jwts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/12/04/secure-microservices-api-keys-access-tokens-and-signed-jwts.html</guid><description>Some samples demonstrating how to secure your microservices using API keys, access tokens, and JSON Web Tokens (JWTs).
Continue with post on IBM developerWorks</description></item><item><title>Using Grok filters to parse Liberty Logs</title><link>/2015/09/02/logstash-and-liberty-optimizing-data-collection-for-the-cloud.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/09/02/logstash-and-liberty-optimizing-data-collection-for-the-cloud.html</guid><description>Logstash is a core part of the ELK stack that can be used to pull and tag content in WAS Liberty logs. This post walks through how to configure Logstash to collect and format WAS Liberty logs.
Continue with post on IBM DeveloperWorks</description></item><item><title>Docker script for AnyConnect on OSX</title><link>/2015/08/25/docker-script-for-anyconnect-on-osx.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/08/25/docker-script-for-anyconnect-on-osx.html</guid><description>I am queen of laziness, and I have to use AnyConnect, and that screws with Docker, and then I have to go looking to remember the magic incantation to get things right...
Who has time for that? I made a script that wraps the whole thing up and reminds me what I should do when it doesn't work.
Instead of: &amp;gt; docker-machine env default
I do this instead, and the script does the rest: &amp;gt; . dockerEnv
The contents of the script are pretty trivial (I am sure shell wizards can find plenty wrong with it, starting with the direct reference to bash, but whatever. Laziness, right?): #!/bin/bash UP=`docker-machine status default` if [ "$UP" != "Running" ] ; then echo "Starting default docker VM" docker-machine start default fi eval "$(docker-machine env default)" export DM_IP=$(docker-machine ip default) echo $DM_IP DM_SUBNET=192.168.$(echo $DM_IP| cut -d'.' -f 3) RESULT=`netstat -rn | grep $DM_SUBNET | grep vboxnet` if [ "$RESULT" = "" ] ; then echo "Adding route for vboxnet0" sudo route -nv add -net $DM_SUBNET -interface vboxnet0 RESULT=`netstat -rn | grep $DM_SUBNET | grep vboxnet` if [ $RESULT = "" ] ; then echo "Quit AnyConnect and re-run this script." exit fi fi docker-machine ls [edit on 3 Sept: updated for even better-ness. Laziness rocks.]</description></item><item><title>Don't Wait! Play with Async EE7 instead</title><link>/2015/08/21/don-t-wait-build-responsive-applications-with-java-ee-7-instead.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/08/21/don-t-wait-build-responsive-applications-with-java-ee-7-instead.html</guid><description>An overview of what Java EE 7 brings in support of responsive applications with samples on GitHub. These samples were also used at IBM InterConnect earlier in the year.
Continue with post on IBM DeveloperWorks</description></item><item><title>Building portable, 12-factor microservices with WAS Liberty and Bluemix</title><link>/2015/08/12/building-portable-12-factor-microservices-with-was-liberty-and-bluemix.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/08/12/building-portable-12-factor-microservices-with-was-liberty-and-bluemix.html</guid><description>An overview of 12-factor applications, and how a 12-factor application can be built using WAS Liberty and Bluemix.
Continue with post on IBM DeveloperWorks</description></item><item><title>Crib notes: Docker on OSX</title><link>/2015/03/31/crib-notes-docker-on-osx.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/03/31/crib-notes-docker-on-osx.html</guid><description> Of course I'm messing with Docker (isn't everyone)? But as most people using OS X are discovering, there are some hiccups. Here are some notes for myself (and perhaps for others) about what is required to make docker work well on OS X: How to Use Docker on OS X: The Missing Guide Most helpful (and a simultaneous &amp;#8216;duh' moment) was his reminder: boot2docker is the host image for docker on OS X, so when docker maps ports, it maps them to boot2docker, and not to OS X itself. So there are some extra things that need to be done to make that work. He has lots of useful suggestions. I also use AnyConnect, which introduces it's own fun, as it likes to rewrite the routing table for giggles. I am thankfully not the only one with this problem. So there were good things to be gleaned here, too.</description></item><item><title>Crib notes: ubuntu 14.04 badness</title><link>/2015/03/31/crib-notes-ubuntu-1404-badness.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2015/03/31/crib-notes-ubuntu-1404-badness.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Woopsie. Somehow, with some update, I managed to screw nvidia up properly, and then in fixing that, I broke symantec antivirus, too. Part of it was that the 14.04 ubuntu headers have moved up, but the kernel was still at an older version, which made dkms pissy, and .. well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Updating to Yosemite: clean install with a clever backup</title><link>/2014/12/30/updating-to-yosemite-clean-install-with-a-clever-backup.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/12/30/updating-to-yosemite-clean-install-with-a-clever-backup.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I upgraded my iMac (which is aging, sadly) to Yosemite while taking a break from work. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted to do a clean install: the drive had two partitions, one an old windows partition that we don't use anymore, and the other was full of crap from years of trying out apps and the migration from Snow Leopard to Lion to Mountain Lion to Mavericks, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted to make a full backup, so I could recover all of my settings and go scrounge around for files that I missed, etc., but I didn't want to clone a drive. I stumbled on these: &lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.theinstructional.com/guides/disk-management-from-the-command-line-part-3">Disk Management from the Command-Line,&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://osxdaily.com/2012/05/23/create-disk-image-of-mac-hard-drive/">How to create a disk image of an entire mac hard drive&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Can you see my plan? It worked very well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping ubuntu server on an external drive</title><link>/2014/08/29/ubuntu-bootstrap.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2014/08/29/ubuntu-bootstrap.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a new 2TB drive that I am going to use to replace a drive on a much used server that is currently running gentoo (which I have increasingly less time to tend). So. I have this new drive in an external enclosure, and I want to bootstrap it with the new OS without having to do that &amp;#8220;go reboot your computer with a &lt;span class="caps">USB&lt;/span> key thing&amp;#8221;. I want my OS on the disk, I want to test that all the services can be coerced to behave the way I need them to behave, and I want to do all this with a minimum of fuss and gymnastics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DIY paper planner - with a cover</title><link>/2013/09/24/diy-paper-planner-with-a-cover.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/09/24/diy-paper-planner-with-a-cover.html</guid><description>&lt;p>So. It took one day, and I had to make a cover. I couldn't help myself. Thankfully, I have more scrapbooking supplies lying around than I know what to do with, so it didn't take too long. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted pockets. I wanted pseudo-lamination. I wanted something that could still flex backwards. No problem, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DIY paper planner</title><link>/2013/09/23/diy-paper-planner.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2013/09/23/diy-paper-planner.html</guid><description>&lt;img src="/images/4t.png" class="right-box" title="Cover view" alt="Cover view" />
&lt;p>Those that have known me for a long time know that I am a sucker for planner. The trouble is that I don't use them much beyond the new planner honeymoon period (for any number of reasons). &lt;/p>
&lt;p>With two kids and a change of house coming, I needed to do something for my overloaded brain, and no combination of apps on the phone is doing the job. Hubby and I do use Google calendars for a somewhat shared brain (at least with regard to who should be where and when), but I don't like Google tasks much (and can't unload work brain there, anyway). I also prefer hand-written lists and notes: I end up with little notes everywhere which doesn't help when you're already feeling overwhelmed!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I stumbled on &lt;span class="caps">DIY&lt;/span> planner printables on Pinterest, and it got me thinking. None of the ones I saw were quite right, and I realized a few reasons why:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>they tend to be over-regimented&lt;/li>
&lt;li>many split up or squish the weekend in the week view&lt;/li>
&lt;li>many use a lot of color, which is nice, but I have a black and white laser printer, so all that flash is lost on me&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>With all of that in mind, I made my own. It is sparse and unadorned, and has few boxes dedicated to this or that kind of note (to do, shopping list, contact list, etc.). This thing is basically all a to-do list of sorts, and I wanted to give myself room (with pen/pencil) to evolve how it works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>lubuntu 11.04 on a thinkpad w520</title><link>/2011/10/11/lubuntu-1104-on-thinkpad-w520.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2011/10/11/lubuntu-1104-on-thinkpad-w520.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting ready to do some travelling for work (Hooray for people that &lt;a href="http://wasdev.net">love our alpha&lt;/a>!), and figured I should move things from my much beloved purple Dell (which is the quadcore I got when I needed one), to the Lenovo Thinkpad W520 that is my official business issued laptop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ubuntu 10.10: sound crackling (especially pidgin), and fluxbox crashes</title><link>/2010/10/26/ubuntu-1010-sound-crackling-especially-pidgin-and-fluxbox-crashes.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/10/26/ubuntu-1010-sound-crackling-especially-pidgin-and-fluxbox-crashes.html</guid><description> I think I should have stayed w/ 10.04. The audio was cracking: known issue with a fix. After applying that, pidgin alert sounds were still crackling. I had to go into pidgin prefs and change the method from Automatic to ALSA. The real bugger is that fluxbox keeps crashing. I have gnome running (session manager, session prefs, etc.), but am using fluxbox as a window manager. I'm sorry.. all the compiz stuff looks cool, but once you start stacking/grouping windows, it's really hard to get used to a window manager that won't do it. I had fluxbox working as the window manager with Lucid (10.04) without issue, but for some reason, flux crashes a _lot_ with 10.10. Pain. (it's thankfully easy to restart flux without having to log out/in.. but still).</description></item><item><title>DNS-323: FFP on a stick, nightly rsync backup...</title><link>/2010/08/21/dns-323-ffp-on-stick-nightly-rsync-backup.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/08/21/dns-323-ffp-on-stick-nightly-rsync-backup.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a lot of things working well, gathered from a lot of resources. I tweaked some scripts to make them work better:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I created an /ffp/&lt;hostname> directory for my personal scripts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have an rsync script that mirrors the ffp installation on the USB stick (/mnt/usb/ffp) to the primary hard drive (/mnt/HD_a2). This means I only have to maintain the USB-copy, but if the USB is not available, I'll still have working stuff on the regular drive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have a few (small) scripts that I use for cron jobs, rather than putting it all directly into the cron task: has the advantage of being able to use logger to add syslog messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>DNS-323: Finally back to it (SSH/busybox)</title><link>/2010/05/16/dns-323-finally-back-to-it-sshbusybox.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/05/16/dns-323-finally-back-to-it-sshbusybox.html</guid><description>&lt;p>After a long hiatus, I'm back to trying to finish customizing our NAS; life with kid means your extra time doesn't always get spent the way you'd like, and I've migrated to a new laptop running ubuntu en route, I should write about that, too.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DNS-323: Initial set-up</title><link>/2010/04/01/dns-323-initial-set-up.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/01/dns-323-initial-set-up.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I purchased (a shamefully long time ago, welcome to tech live as a mom with a toddler) a DNS-323 (and two 1T drives) with the hope of moving most of our shared files onto it. Now that we don't record TV shows anymore, having that box on all the time is just a power drain. So: the goal is a DNS-323 with all of our files (photos, music, finance stuff, some movies, etc.) onto the first volume of that drive, and then using an rsync shadow with hardlinks to do nightly backups to the second drive. Some RAID configurations have been reported as less than stable, and using a mirror configuration requires both drives to be active: a nightly rsync backup will do.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Movies schmovies</title><link>/2010/04/01/movies-schmovies.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/01/movies-schmovies.html</guid><description>Want to get DVDs playing on the laptop that is running gentoo that I'll only have to use for a few more days before I get a new shiny (purple!) one. I know, makes no sense.. but hey, learning is good, right? Use xine-ui. It got the farthest first. Make sure your region is set Go through the few hoops you need to get raw i/o working. I pegged/tanked RAM w/o raw access -- every player segfaulted as a result (mplayer, xine, vlc). Use the raw device. If it's an encrypted DVD (and you have libdvdcss installed), I found that I needed to change something in my environment to get it to correctly decrypt the disk: export DVDCSS_METHOD=disc -- I did it on the command line since I was just testing. Setting this finally let the DVD play.. with dropped frames all over the place.. but still.. progress! And last, but not least, the simplest instruction from xine's help: change the niceness level of xine.. nice --5 xine And poof! movie! with menu! rock on</description></item><item><title>Amen for schedtool</title><link>/2010/01/13/amen-for-schedtool.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/01/13/amen-for-schedtool.html</guid><description> How did I not know about this sooner? Trying to build a particularly large maven project would consume so much CPU that my poor laptop would quit because it was sweating too much. I used schedtool to set an affinity to only one of the two CPUs available on my dual-core laptop for the shell I used to launch the build, and voila! Things don't get as hot, and my system stays responsive. *phew!* schedtool</description></item><item><title>Upgrading old rails apps...</title><link>/2010/01/04/upgrading-old-rails-apps.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/01/04/upgrading-old-rails-apps.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I have to say that updating RoR for old apps always lands me in some wonky funny business: missing config variables, moved whatsits and thingummies. grr. The issues aren't easy to search for, either.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ejecting the CD when things are hosed...</title><link>/2007/12/31/ejecting-cd-when-things-are-hosed.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/31/ejecting-cd-when-things-are-hosed.html</guid><description> So, in starting to set up bootcamp, I totally managed to f something up! (Yes, I can even break a Mac). I tried the usual turn off / turn on the machine, and CRAP! the CD is still in the drive, and it HAS NO BUTTONS. Eject is totally software driven.
Thankfully, someone already took the time to list all of the interesting things you should try to get your CD back. Number 3 did the trick.
The iTunes eject button Disk Utility ... Hold down mouse button at startup Hold down C key at startup Start up into Open Firmware ... Start up in Target FireWire mode ... Start up from another machine Take your machine to an Apple Store</description></item><item><title>Happy Solstice!</title><link>/2007/12/21/happy-solstice.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/12/21/happy-solstice.html</guid><description>The longest night of the year has come.. the shortest day of the year is done, and I... well.
So there was this box. It got shipped here a little while ago. It's large, squarish, and only about a foot and a half deep. It's been sitting in the dining room by the skimpily ornamented Norfolk pine and the tiny Meyer lemon tree (which is just beside itself with lemons on the make, but that's another story).
Chris was very careful that I not see anything about it (I also was honest and didn't go looking.. I mean, what's the fun of that?), but he has asked me to guess what it was.. "A spare tire", "A wall-hanging jewelry closet", "A mirror"... The closest I could come (and I didn't think I had a chance in hell of it being so) was a big beautiful LCD monitor to replace the monstrosity on my desk downstairs.
And Lo! it was a big beautiful LCD monitor.. complete with a bluetooth wireless keyboard and mouse. My husband, that wonderful man, gifted me an iMac.
Yesss..</description></item><item><title>Well, as Jon was bugging me about it..</title><link>/2007/07/02/well-as-jon-was-bugging-me-about-it.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/07/02/well-as-jon-was-bugging-me-about-it.html</guid><description>I have, in fact, begun publishing my scans on deviantArt.. I told you I wanted to get prints of some of them.. ;)
The scanning has only just begun, though, so be patient. Some of these images have spent too long in a sketchbook rubbing against other pages.. so it's hard to get the scan so it doesn't look so darn grainy. *sigh*</description></item><item><title>Fixing ATI again..</title><link>/2007/06/24/fixing-ati-again.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/06/24/fixing-ati-again.html</guid><description> I'm also rebuilding my T60p in place (meaning I started half of it while chrooted, and have now switched over to the newer half...).
I've run into a new issue loading the dri drivers: AIGLX error: dlopen of /usr/lib/dri/fglrx_dri.so failed (/usr/lib/dri/fglrx_dri.so: undefined symbol: __glXFindDRIScreen). Moving to the latest ati driver seemed to fix that (8.37.6-r1).
ATI Linux drivers for debian has great information around how to configure X11 to work with the proprietary ati drivers. Fglrx - ThinkWiki is a good source for how this stuff all works with thinkpads...</description></item><item><title>Scanning in my pencil sketches...</title><link>/2007/06/24/scanning-in-my-pencil-sketches.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/06/24/scanning-in-my-pencil-sketches.html</guid><description> So, I blew some time this weekend working on getting some of my pencil sketches scanned in the right way (why I decide the summer is the time to try this stuff.. ). There are a few of them I've been lugging along in my silly sketchbook, and I really like them.. which actually makes me less likely to carry the thing along, because it could mess up some of those doodles I really like.
So. I started by *gasp* removing them all from my little sketch book. I happen (because I'm a dork) to be equipped with things to make a nice portfolio with these sketches in them because of other crafty things, so I know where they'll end up. BUT.. before they go there, I'd like to get some high-quality scans of them (I'd like to be able to make prints of at least one..).
Anyway, after wasting scads of time, I can agree that the following links have whatchya need: Scanning pencil drawings (question in forum thread) Extending dynamic range (resulting HOW-TO)
I've been going back and forth between the two plugins mentioned in the posts above, and I'm also hovering between the two methods (two gimp plugins: dynamic range extender (DRE) or HDR tone mapping). As I go, I have been slowly leaning towards the first (which is what the author used for the example in the HOW-TO), mostly because I can then scan and work with the image all in grayscale (the HDR plugin assumes RGB mode). Not sure which is better in the end, but I'm finding the output from the DRE plugin to be more direct.
Scan w/ XSane: Standard options window: Brightness (1, 0, -2 or -3), Sharpness 1 Created a "pencil sketch" medium: Gray with 1.0 Gamma, and -100/100 brightness/contrast (basically telling the xsane post-scanning processor to leave it alone)</description></item><item><title>Emergency brain</title><link>/2007/03/30/emergency-brain.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/03/30/emergency-brain.html</guid><description>Thank goodness I have a functioning emergency brain. I've never needed to know that I even had one, much less whether or not it worked, until the unfortunate events of the past few weeks unfolded. My Dad was in a very unfortunate accident at work. Rather than bandy on about it here, I'll send you to the site we've created to share the news (my Dad has a rather large fan club.;) ).
http://mike.haaser.com</description></item><item><title>When and where to use images..</title><link>/2007/03/07/when-and-where-to-use-images.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/03/07/when-and-where-to-use-images.html</guid><description>I just read/skimmed Naughty or Nice? CSS Background Images [http://24ways.org/]. Now this is an old post (2005), and I don't remember how I stumbled on it, but the post makes a good point - don't stick in CSS what should be delivered via content. I always try (with mixed success, I admit - it depends on how much control I have) to load my pages in lynx or some other text based browser to make sure I can still get around. I increasingly find sites that are not navigable sans full-graphical-browser tricks.</description></item><item><title>DNS Monster</title><link>/2007/03/02/dns-monster.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/03/02/dns-monster.html</guid><description>So. For a few reasons, I have been moving my websites and domains off to hostmonster: a) free transfer + renewal; b) registerfly has been sucking, and some of my domains got caught in the registerfly/enom.com fiasco, and I really just want to get them the hell out, c) hostmonster has ssh, php, mysql, ruby on rails - pretty much anything I ever wanted to tinker with, d) I can stick however many domains on my account that I want to. The downside: CPanel, and DNS manipulation. I am used to having my hands right on the DNS records - with CPanel, not only can I not touch the records, but in certain cases, they have rules (either self imposed or imposed by CPanel's Web Host Manager thing) that just plain prevent me from doing what I want. I hate not being able to do what I want. (whine whine whine).
But look what I found: EditDNS.net - A DNS provider of free web hosting and a bunch of other goodies. They thrive on donations of course, but still... worth a try, I think.</description></item><item><title>Gentoo and an IBM T60p - Part 2: Dual Boot / NTFS</title><link>/2007/01/05/gentoo-and-an-ibm-t60p-part-2-dual-boot-ntfs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/01/05/gentoo-and-an-ibm-t60p-part-2-dual-boot-ntfs.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I have what I tried below, but I eventually dropped the attempt. The Lenovo modules hung up &lt;span class="caps">VMW&lt;/span>are any time I tried to boot it that way, and while I could mount the &lt;span class="caps">NTFS&lt;/span> partition used by WinXP R/W with the tools below, I could not easily get WinXP to look at the lion's share of the drive. (My fault, really – if I weren't so attached to other filesystem types, I could probably have made this work).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gentoo and an IBM T60p - Part 3: Networking</title><link>/2007/01/05/gentoo-and-an-ibm-t60p-part-3-networking.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2007/01/05/gentoo-and-an-ibm-t60p-part-3-networking.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting networking up and running on the T60p has been a mixed bag. On one hand, the wired connection was easy (expected). The wireless was at first &lt;span class="caps">REALLY&lt;/span> flaky, then after some fiddling the connection at home (&lt;span class="caps">WEP&lt;/span>) was functional, and as of now (when I'm finally posting this thing) it still doesn't work at work (&lt;span class="caps">LEAP&lt;/span>). &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rails: Staying away from Enums in Migrations</title><link>/2006/12/29/rails-staying-away-from-enums-in-migrations.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/12/29/rails-staying-away-from-enums-in-migrations.html</guid><description>I was fiddling with migrations, and found these regarding the use of MySQL-ish ENUMs in Migrations:
Enum fields in migrations? [rails.techno-weenie.net] HowtoUseSetAndEnumColumns [wiki.rubyonrails.com] Basically, ENUMs aren't supported, and using Validations might be a good work-around, but is dependent on you putting (and keeping) all of the logic in your Rails app. If you need to go cross-app (with some other thing that ain't rails), then use CHECK or other DB constraints to enforce desired values.</description></item><item><title>Gentoo and an IBM T60p - Part 1: Installation and X</title><link>/2006/12/18/gentoo-and-an-ibm-t60p-part-1-installation-and-x.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/12/18/gentoo-and-an-ibm-t60p-part-1-installation-and-x.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Got a new T60 &lt;strong>yay!&lt;/strong>, here's my brain dump on getting it to work with gentoo (2006.1).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See also (Updated as new parts are added):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/config/261/GentooandanIBMT60pPart2">Part 2: &lt;span class="caps">NTFS&lt;/span>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/config/260/GentooandanIBMT60pPart3">Part 3: Networking&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Rails: Printing validation errors as flash notices</title><link>/2006/07/11/rails-printing-validation-errors-as-flash-notices.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/07/11/rails-printing-validation-errors-as-flash-notices.html</guid><description> I am quite sure someone has already found this simple solution, but when I poked around, I couldn't find it.
Here is my snippet to print out the error messages resulting from a validation as a flash notice:
if @user.save flash[:'notice'] = &amp;quot;New user saved successfully.&amp;quot; elsif !@user.errors.empty? flash[:'notice'] = &amp;quot;Could not save new user: &amp;quot; &amp;lt;&amp;lt; @user.errors.full_messages.join(&amp;quot;; &amp;quot;) end</description></item><item><title>Ruby and Rails</title><link>/2006/03/05/rails.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2006/03/05/rails.html</guid><description>&lt;p>So. I'm fiddling. again. with Ruby on Rails. because it's trendy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have to say, it's also handy. Very nice not to have to write the entire DB framework just to make an app! The problem that I have is I'm such a habitual programming dork that I find Ruby's syntax a little odd...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gentoo/T40: Nailing down wireless config</title><link>/2005/07/01/gentoot40-nailing-down-wireless-config.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/07/01/gentoot40-nailing-down-wireless-config.html</guid><description> Gathering some links to get wireless working (better) on my T40. I'm trying to figure out how to get some semblance of roaming... sigh
References:
HOWTO Wireless Configuration and Startup [gentoo-wiki.com] Wireless Networking [Gentoo Linux Handbook]</description></item><item><title>TXP Hack: centralizing priv lookups</title><link>/2005/06/24/TXP-check-privs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/06/24/TXP-check-privs.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I use &lt;span class="caps">HTTP&lt;/span> Auth for one of my Textpattern installations, and so, I wanted people that could get to the textpattern pages to have, by default, staff writer permissions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TXP Hack: Using TXP Excerpts like MT</title><link>/2005/03/06/MT-excerpts-in-TXP.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/03/06/MT-excerpts-in-TXP.html</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things I used heavily in MT was the body/extended body trick. I wanted to continue that with Textpattern, but it involved some hacks to how &lt;span class="caps">TXP &lt;/span>handles excerpts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TXP Hack: MT-Macro like function in textpattern</title><link>/2005/02/23/MT-macro-in-TXP.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/02/23/MT-macro-in-TXP.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a simple hack to add one of my favorite MT-plugins, Brad Choate's &lt;a href="http://www.bradchoate.com/weblog/2002/08/12/mtmacro">&lt;span class="caps">MTM&lt;/span>acros&lt;/a> &lt;span class="attribute">[&lt;a href="http://www.bradchoate.com">bradchoate.com&lt;/a>]&lt;/span>, to textpattern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Granted, I didn't pull the entire kaboodle. This doesn't do fun container logic and acronym matching, etc. But it does do simple string replacement, which is what I used it for (e.g. smilies and pretty attributions).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cleaning up gentoo...</title><link>/2005/01/03/cleaning-up-gentoo.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2005/01/03/cleaning-up-gentoo.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Those distfiles&amp;hellip; /usr/portage/distfiles can get pretty big, and cleaning it out periodically can save a lot of disk space. The brute force approach is to just clear out the whole thing, which can be more practical if you have a fast connection. If redownloading what you need is no big deal, then cleaning out distfiles can be the faster way to go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IBM T40 and multi-channel audio (ALSA)</title><link>/2004/12/19/ibm-t40-linux-and-multi-channel-audio-alsa.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/12/19/ibm-t40-linux-and-multi-channel-audio-alsa.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I'm finally getting around to setting up multi-channel audio. I've had this machine for awhile now, and most things are humming along.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Handy CD reading/writing/ripping stuff</title><link>/2004/12/01/handy-cd-readingwritingripping-stuff.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/12/01/handy-cd-readingwritingripping-stuff.html</guid><description> ISO, CDR, and CDRW in Linux [cpqlinux.com]
An old page, but full of handy tips (more like quick references) nonetheless.
Just in case, it's also here. [waybackmachine.org]
Also:
HOWTO ATAPI CD Burning [gentoo-wiki.com] CD burning with a 2.6 kernel [www.debian-administration.org]</description></item><item><title>ACPI on IBM T40 with 2.6 kernel</title><link>/2004/09/28/acpi-on-ibm-t40-with-26-kernel.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/09/28/acpi-on-ibm-t40-with-26-kernel.html</guid><description>&lt;p>OK. getting ACPI to work properly needed to be revisited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://bellet.info/laptop/t40.html#suspend_resume">Suspend/Resume on T40&lt;/a> &lt;span class="attribute">[&lt;a href="http://bellet.info/">bellet.info&lt;/a>]&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guy originally used APM, but his update on 2004/07/15 makes some good notes, which I followed, notably:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Local APIC is required for USB to function properly, but it borks all over suspend/poweroff processing. There is a simple enough referenced patch to make it behave&amp;#8230;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Gentoo on an IBM T40</title><link>/2004/07/21/gentoo-on-an-ibm-t40.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/07/21/gentoo-on-an-ibm-t40.html</guid><description>&lt;p>So, I have gentoo up and running on my T40, and thought I'd share the resources that helped me get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those interested, here's the currently running kernel &lt;a href="/files/config-2.6.7-gentoo-r11" title="2.6.7-gentoo-r11">config&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TOYS!</title><link>/2004/05/19/toys.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/05/19/toys.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I got a Sony Clie PEG-TJ37. I was thinking about the PEG-TJ55, but I just could NOT deal with the wheel thing in the back – too awkward. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the info on getting this puppy to work with linux seemed a little scattered, I figured I'd make my notes here, maybe someone else would find them handy, too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2.6.3 Kernel on IBM T23</title><link>/2004/02/19/263-kernel-on-ibm-t23.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/02/19/263-kernel-on-ibm-t23.html</guid><description>Well, this is first pass, I'll record it anyway.
APM doesn't work – suspend does strange things. alsasound in the kernel works well – used mm-sources, and everything went smoothly. I don't remember any major issues.
config-2.6.3-rc1-mm1
Notes on APM with 2.6 kernel:
T23 suspend – 2.6.0 final
T23 suspend – 2.6.0 final</description></item><item><title>Helpful stuff for kernel 2.6.x and X (mice/keyboard)</title><link>/2004/02/19/helpful-stuff-for-kernel-26x-and-x-micekeyboard.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/02/19/helpful-stuff-for-kernel-26x-and-x-micekeyboard.html</guid><description> Linux: 2.6 Input Drivers FAQ
Didn't want to lose it.. Additional keyboard stuff:
Keyboard-and-Console-HOWTO</description></item><item><title>Linux/T23 - Dual Monitors</title><link>/2004/01/20/linuxt23-dual-monitors.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2004/01/20/linuxt23-dual-monitors.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Trying to get dual monitors working..&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CDRW on IBM T23 with Gentoo</title><link>/2003/12/19/cdrw-on-ibm-t23-with-gentoo.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2003/12/19/cdrw-on-ibm-t23-with-gentoo.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Didn't notice until now that my CD-RW/DVD player wasn't loading properly – you can tell how much I use it, eh? &lt;img alt=";-&amp;#41;" src="/images/smilies/wink2.gif" class="icon" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'd already built the kernel with the correct SCSI modules (see references, below). I'd also already added &lt;code>"hdc=ide-scsi"&lt;/code> to my grub boot parameters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fixing Sound/Suspend-Resume on IBM T23 for Gentoo</title><link>/2003/12/19/fixing-soundsuspend-resume-on-ibm-t23-for-gentoo.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2003/12/19/fixing-soundsuspend-resume-on-ibm-t23-for-gentoo.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="caps">ALSA&lt;/span> does work, as I mentioned &lt;a href="{{site.baseurl}}{% link _posts/2003-09-21-dammit-gentoo-on-t23-continued.html %}">here&lt;/a>, but it seems to have problems across a suspend-resume, i.e. it doesn't work post-resume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously used patches don't seem to apply to newer Alsa modules.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It's Alive!! (Gentoo and T23)</title><link>/2003/09/29/its-alive-gentoo-and-t23.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2003/09/29/its-alive-gentoo-and-t23.html</guid><description>&lt;p>So a comment on the first of my entries about Gentoo on a T23 reminded me to make an update regarding my now working system...&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also sorted out my &lt;a href="{{ site.baseurl }}{% link _posts/2003-09-22-gentoo-t23-and-vmware.html %}">&lt;span class="caps">VMW&lt;/span>are issues&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gentoo, T23, and VMWare</title><link>/2003/09/22/gentoo-t23-and-vmware.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2003/09/22/gentoo-t23-and-vmware.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://lindows.prodigydigital.com/tutorials/vmware.html">Why do I have to run vmware-config.pl every time I reboot my computer?&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was happening to me, and while that's a lindows tutorial, it hit the nail on the head:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>&lt;p>Because devfs rebuilds the /dev tree at each reboot, it is likely that your vmnet and vmmon devices will become unavailable. Because those devices are now unavailable, you have to manually run the vmware-config.pl to rebuild them into the existing /dev tree.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>[UPDATE: 9/29/2004]&lt;/strong> This is total hogwash, see &lt;a href="{{ site.baseurl }}{% link _posts/2003-09-29-its-alive-gentoo-and-t23.html %}">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dammit- Gentoo on T23 continued</title><link>/2003/09/21/dammit-gentoo-on-t23-continued.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2003/09/21/dammit-gentoo-on-t23-continued.html</guid><description>&lt;p>So everything was working flawlessly, and I had to switch over into Mandrake to get something, and when I rebooted to Gentoo again, chaos reigned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, not quite chaos, but several modules were refusing to load, with lots of scary messages about IRQ settings and other hogwash.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gentoo on a T23</title><link>/2003/09/19/gentoo-on-a-t23.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2003/09/19/gentoo-on-a-t23.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Audio: &lt;a href="http://www.intel.com/support/graphics/linux/audio.htm">Intel i810&lt;/a>,&lt;br />
Alsa &lt;a href="http://www.alsa-project.org/alsa-doc/doc-php/template.php3?company=Intel&amp;amp;card=i820&amp;amp;chip=i820&amp;amp;module=intel8x0">snd-intel8&amp;#215;0&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Video: &lt;a href="http://www.probo.com/timr/savage40.html">S3 Savage IX&lt;/a> , &lt;a href="http://www.dotfiles.com/files/13/311_XF86Config-T23.txt">Sample XF86Config&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just about everything: &lt;span class="caps">IBM&lt;/span> 82801CAM &lt;a href="ftp://download.intel.com/design/chipsets/datashts/29071601.pdf">chipsets&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gentoooooooooooooooooooooo</title><link>/2003/09/16/gentoooooooooooooooooooooo.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2003/09/16/gentoooooooooooooooooooooo.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Jimminy Christmas!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything was paddling along smoothly until I hit this little hiccup, I've got an ATI RADEON card, which is apparently a whole pile of badness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank goodness some punks have figured this crap out before me!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>