<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nas on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/nas.html</link><description>Recent content in nas on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/nas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DNS-323: FFP on a stick, nightly rsync backup...</title><link>/2010/08/21/dns-323-ffp-on-stick-nightly-rsync-backup.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/08/21/dns-323-ffp-on-stick-nightly-rsync-backup.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a lot of things working well, gathered from a lot of resources. I tweaked some scripts to make them work better:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I created an /ffp/&lt;hostname> directory for my personal scripts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have an rsync script that mirrors the ffp installation on the USB stick (/mnt/usb/ffp) to the primary hard drive (/mnt/HD_a2). This means I only have to maintain the USB-copy, but if the USB is not available, I'll still have working stuff on the regular drive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have a few (small) scripts that I use for cron jobs, rather than putting it all directly into the cron task: has the advantage of being able to use logger to add syslog messages.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>DNS-323: Finally back to it (SSH/busybox)</title><link>/2010/05/16/dns-323-finally-back-to-it-sshbusybox.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/05/16/dns-323-finally-back-to-it-sshbusybox.html</guid><description>&lt;p>After a long hiatus, I'm back to trying to finish customizing our NAS; life with kid means your extra time doesn't always get spent the way you'd like, and I've migrated to a new laptop running ubuntu en route, I should write about that, too.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DNS-323: Initial set-up</title><link>/2010/04/01/dns-323-initial-set-up.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2010/04/01/dns-323-initial-set-up.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I purchased (a shamefully long time ago, welcome to tech live as a mom with a toddler) a DNS-323 (and two 1T drives) with the hope of moving most of our shared files onto it. Now that we don't record TV shows anymore, having that box on all the time is just a power drain. So: the goal is a DNS-323 with all of our files (photos, music, finance stuff, some movies, etc.) onto the first volume of that drive, and then using an rsync shadow with hardlinks to do nightly backups to the second drive. Some RAID configurations have been reported as less than stable, and using a mirror configuration requires both drives to be active: a nightly rsync backup will do.
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>