<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>quarkus on ebullient·works</title><link>/tags/quarkus.html</link><description>Recent content in quarkus on ebullient·works</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/quarkus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quarkus and Camel in bites: REST endpoints</title><link>/2023/02/10/quarkus-camel-in-bites-rest.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/02/10/quarkus-camel-in-bites-rest.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Learning things a teensy bit at a time. While my ultimate goal is to do pretty much anything other than REST, I still have this nice shiny svelte front-end that needs to pull some things from the co-resident Quarkus app. I could, of course, provide that information in &amp;ldquo;the usual way&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m exploring Camel here, which means I should try doing it that way, instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using Quarkus and Camel together is a bit of a brain-bender, as you&amp;rsquo;re overlapping two environments that are totally independent and overlapping, but it does work, and I can see some glimmers of why, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve grown up thinking about things as RestTemplates or JAX-RS resources, it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; very different.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iterative development with Quarkus and Svelte, care of Quinoa</title><link>/2023/02/07/iterative-development-quarkus-svelte-quinoa.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2023/02/07/iterative-development-quarkus-svelte-quinoa.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Another conference is coming up, and I&amp;rsquo;m writing another ridiculous frankenstein app for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this revision, I am going to add a local-only Web UI for a few reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This app is still mostly command-line driven, but some configuration options are awkward to set as arguments, and manually editing a config file is &amp;hellip; meh.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I haven&amp;rsquo;t done any serious front-end UI work in a really long time. The UI for &lt;a href="https://github.com/gameontext/gameon-webapp">Game On! Text adventure&lt;/a> is overdue for an overhaul, it&amp;rsquo;s an Angular 1 app. I know, I know. Don&amp;rsquo;t judge me.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Between one thing and another, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing more TypeScript alongside my Java and because of some collaboration on plugins for &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian.md&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;ve been bumping up against Svelte. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use this little project to actually figure out how Svelte works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This project will then have:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://quarkus.io/">Quarkus&lt;/a> as the main CLI driver that will sometimes wait around for awhile while you fuss around with a Web UI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte&lt;/a> to create a UI that feels nice to use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://maven.apache.org/">Maven&lt;/a> for building Java things&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nodejs.org/en/">Node&lt;/a> + &lt;a href="https://vitejs.dev/">Vite&lt;/a> for TypeScript tooling&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>On the surface, the above sounds like a big mess, right? I&amp;rsquo;m installing double the tools, having to do this build in two steps, and then do the fancy dance to get the Node stuff in the right place in the Java stuff, and deal with making native images happy, and&amp;hellip; &lt;em>gross&lt;/em> 🤢.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankfully, &lt;a href="https://github.com/ia3andy">Andy Damevin&lt;/a> has already come to provide the rescue I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I would need. He created the &lt;a href="https://quarkiverse.github.io/quarkiverse-docs/quarkus-quinoa/dev/index.html">Quinoa extension&lt;/a>, and I am a fan! 🎉&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Quinoa extension manages building and packaging the embedded Web UI with its preferred tools. So the outer Maven build can carry on doing its thing, and the Quinoa extension will invoke the appropriate node scripts to build and package the Web UI, and tuck them in the right place for serving with an uber jar or native binary. Not only that, but it integrates Quarkus dev mode with the web framework&amp;rsquo;s live coding support, which means you just keep coding and the entire web app evolves as you go. Holy cow, it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Devoxx UK 2022: Take a walk on the cient side</title><link>/2022/05/18/pockets-command-line-apps-at-devoxx-uk.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/05/18/pockets-command-line-apps-at-devoxx-uk.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I spoke about creating command line applications at DevNexus in May. I wanted to change a few things the second time around, to see if I could get farther along with the application, but I was stymied again! No one texted me this time. Instead, my ipad and laptop fought with the projector over screen resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="/images/2022-05-twitter-devoxxuk.png"
alt="Coding in the air" width="400px"/>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>DevNexus 2022: Take a walk on the cient side</title><link>/2022/04/18/pockets-command-line-apps-at-devnexus.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/04/18/pockets-command-line-apps-at-devnexus.html</guid><description>A new talk! I have two recorded versions, but few charts, as this one was mostly code.
My daughter figured out how to text me in the middle of it. The notifications appeared on my ipad, so I could see them while the audience couldn&amp;rsquo;t, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to know if you would have been able to keep a straight face as the notifications arrived: &amp;ldquo;mom&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;mom&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;mom&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
The subject of the talk is a little command line application called &amp;ldquo;Pockets&amp;rdquo;, and it lives here: https://github.com/ebullient/pockets-cli</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #81 (host): Morphia and MongoDB object-document mapping</title><link>/2022/02/21/qi-morphia-and-mongodb.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/02/21/qi-morphia-and-mongodb.html</guid><description>Justin Lee drops by to discuss MongoDB object-document mapping with the Quarkus Morphia extension.
We talk about Morphia, MongoDB, and the whens/whys of &amp;ldquo;NoSQL&amp;rdquo; vs. SQL data sources.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #80 (co-host): Neo4j with Quarkus</title><link>/2022/02/14/qi-neo4j-with-quarkus.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/02/14/qi-neo4j-with-quarkus.html</guid><description>Max and I talked to Michael Simons about the creation of the Neo4j Quarkus extension, from understanding Quarkus&amp;rsquo;s extension model, to a deep dive into how Quarkus helps create native images via GraalVM.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #77 (co-host): Quarkus Renarde - a server-side web framework experiment</title><link>/2022/01/25/qi-quarkus-renarde.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/01/25/qi-quarkus-renarde.html</guid><description>Max and I talk to Stéphane Épardaud about his experiment making a server-side web framework.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #76 (guest): Quarkus Q&amp;A</title><link>/2022/01/17/qi-quarkus-q-a.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2022/01/17/qi-quarkus-q-a.html</guid><description>Max, Jason, Georgios and I all got together to answer questions about Quarkus.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #71 (co-host): Using JReleaser with Quarkus</title><link>/2021/11/22/qi-using-jreleaser-with-quarkus.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/11/22/qi-using-jreleaser-with-quarkus.html</guid><description>Andres Almiray joins us to discuss how to package and release Quarkus applications with JReleaser.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #67 (guest): Testing command mode</title><link>/2021/10/18/qi-cli-testing.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/10/18/qi-cli-testing.html</guid><description>Host, or Guest? It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.
Max and I discuss different testing strategies for command mode applications (or command-line interfaces (CLIs) if you prefer).</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #59 (host): Quarkus projects using MicroProfile specs with Giuseppe</title><link>/2021/08/09/qi-host-projects-with-microprofile.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/08/09/qi-host-projects-with-microprofile.html</guid><description>Giuseppe Scaramuzzino @GiuseScara comes by to discuss his youtube channel, tutorials and building Quarkus projects using MicroProfile specifications.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #58 (host): Sanne talks about Hibernate ORM and GraalVM native images</title><link>/2021/07/19/qi-host-duties-sanne-and-hibernate-orm.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/07/19/qi-host-duties-sanne-and-hibernate-orm.html</guid><description>Being a co-host is hard work, especially while in (yet another) remote location.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #57 (guest): Quarkus CLI</title><link>/2021/06/14/qi-new-quarkus-cli.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/06/14/qi-new-quarkus-cli.html</guid><description>A video in which live coding happens, and I don&amp;rsquo;t mess up too badly.</description></item><item><title>airhacks.fm: MicroProfile Metrics, Micrometer and Quarkus — podcast with Adam Bien</title><link>/2021/05/12/airhacks-fm-microprofile-metrics-micrometer-and-quarkus.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/05/12/airhacks-fm-microprofile-metrics-micrometer-and-quarkus.html</guid><description>&lt;p>I thoroughly enjoy talking with Adam. We sat down awhile ago to talk about metrics: who needs them, what they are for.. and some other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="embed-container">
&lt;iframe allow="autoplay" width="100%" height="200" src="https://www.iheart.com/podcast/256-airhacksfm-podcast-with-ad-43073886/episode/microprofile-metrics-micrometer-and-quarkus-82456755/?embed=true" frameborder="0">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #47 (host): Keycloak's Journey to Quarkus</title><link>/2021/05/03/qi-keycloak-journey-to-quarkus.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/05/03/qi-keycloak-journey-to-quarkus.html</guid><description>Dimitrios Andreadis and I host Sebastien Blanc and Pedro Igor to talk about Keycloak&amp;rsquo;s journey to Quarkus.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #43 (host): Writing Quarkus Extensions</title><link>/2021/04/07/qi-writing-quarkus-extensions.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/04/07/qi-writing-quarkus-extensions.html</guid><description>A group discussion on how to write Quarkus Extensions with guest Peter Palaga.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #34 (guest): Talking about Quarkus 1.11 Release</title><link>/2021/01/25/qi-1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/01/25/qi-1.html</guid><description>Georgios and I talk about all kinds of things, most of them related to Quarkus 1.11.</description></item><item><title>Quarkus Insights #17 (guest): What's new in Metrics</title><link>/2020/09/14/qi-whats-new-with-metrics.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/09/14/qi-whats-new-with-metrics.html</guid><description>Max and Jason talk to Ken and I to talk about updates to Metrics delivered in Quarkus 1.8.</description></item></channel></rss>